
NAME
    Write-Progress
    
SYNOPSIS
    Displays a progress bar within a Windows PowerShell command window.
    
SYNTAX
    Write-Progress [-Activity] <String> [[-Status] <String>] [[-Id] <Int32>] [-Completed] [-CurrentOperation <String>] 
    [-ParentId <Int32>] [-PercentComplete <Int32>] [-SecondsRemaining <Int32>] [-SourceId <Int32>] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Write-Progress cmdlet displays a progress bar in a Windows PowerShell command window that depicts the status 
    of a running command or script. You can select the indicators that the bar reflects and the text that appears 
    above and below the progress bar.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Activity <String>
        Specifies the first line of text in the heading above the status bar. This text describes the activity whose 
        progress is being reported.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Completed [<SwitchParameter>]
        Indicates whether the progress bar is visible. If this parameter is omitted, Write-Progress displays progress 
        information.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -CurrentOperation <String>
        Specifies the line of text below the progress bar. This text describes the operation that is currently taking 
        place.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Id <Int32>
        Specifies an ID that distinguishes each progress bar from the others. Use this parameter when you are creating 
        more than one progress bar in a single command. If the progress bars do not have different IDs, they are 
        superimposed instead of being displayed in a series.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    3
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -ParentId <Int32>
        Identifies the parent activity of the current activity. Use the value -1 if the current activity has no parent 
        activity.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -PercentComplete <Int32>
        Specifies the percentage of the activity that is completed. Use the value -1 if the percentage complete is 
        unknown or not applicable.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SecondsRemaining <Int32>
        Specifies the projected number of seconds remaining until the activity is completed. Use the value -1 if the 
        number of seconds remaining is unknown or not applicable.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -SourceId <Int32>
        Identifies the source of the record.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Status <String>
        Specifies the second line of text in the heading above the status bar. This text describes current state of 
        the activity.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    2
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, see 
        about_CommonParameters (http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113216). 
    
INPUTS
    None
        
        
    
        You cannot pipe input to this cmdlet.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    None
        
        
    
        Write-Progress does not generate any output.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        If the progress bar does not appear, check the value of the $ProgressPreference variable. If the value is set 
        to SilentlyContinue, the progress bar is not displayed. For more information about Windows PowerShell 
        preferences, see about_Preference_Variables.
        
        The parameters of the cmdlet correspond to the properties of the ProgressRecord class 
        (System.Management.Automation.ProgressRecord). For more information, see the ProgressRecord topic in the 
        Windows PowerShell Software Development Kit (SDK).
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>for ($i = 1; $i -le 100; $i++ )
    {write-progress -activity "Search in Progress" -status "$i% Complete:" -percentcomplete $i;}
    
    
    This command displays the progress of a For loop that counts from 1 to 100. The Write-Progress command includes a 
    status bar heading ("activity"), a status line, and the variable $i (the counter in the For loop), which indicates 
    the relative completeness of the task.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>for($i = 1; $i -lt 101; $i++ )
    {write-progress -activity Updating -status 'Progress->' -percentcomplete $i -currentOperation OuterLoop; `
    for($j = 1; $j -lt 101; $j++ )
    {write-progress -id  1 -activity Updating -status 'Progress' -percentcomplete $j -currentOperation InnerLoop} }
    Updating
    Progress ->
    [ooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo]
    OutsideLoop
    Updating
    Progress
    [oooooooooooooooooo                                                   ]
    InnerLoop
    
    
    This example displays the progress of two nested For loops, each of which is represented by a progress bar.
    
    The Write-Progress command for the second progress bar includes the Id parameter that distinguishes it from the 
    first progress bar. Without the Id parameter, the progress bars would be superimposed on each other instead of 
    being displayed one below the other.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    PS C:\>$events = get-eventlog -logname system
    PS C:\>$events | foreach-object -begin {clear-host;$i=0;$out=""} `
    -process {if($_.message -like "*bios*") {$out=$out + $_.Message}; $i = $i+1;
    write-progress -activity "Searching Events" -status "Progress:" -percentcomplete ($i/$events.count*100)} `
    -end {$out}
    
    
    This command displays the progress of a command to find the string "bios" in the System event log.
    
    In the first line of the command, the Get-EventLog cmdlet gets the events in the System log and stores them in the 
    $events variable.
    
    In the second line, the events are piped to the ForEach-Object cmdlet. Before processing begins, the Clear-Host 
    cmdlet is used to clear the screen, the $i counter variable is set to zero, and the $out output variable is set to 
    the empty string.
    
    In the third line, which is the Process script block of the ForEach-Object cmdlet, the cmdlet searches the message 
    property of each incoming object for "bios". If the string is found, the message is added to $out. Then, the $i 
    counter variable is incremented to record that another event has been examined.
    
    The fourth line uses the Write-Progress cmdlet with values for the Activity and Status text fields that create the 
    first and second lines of the progress bar heading, respectively. The PercentComplete parameter value is 
    calculated by dividing the number of events that have been processed ($i) by the total number of events retrieved 
    ($events.count) and then multiplying that result by 100.
    
    In the last line, the End parameter of the ForEach-Object cmdlet is used to display the messages that are stored 
    in the $out variable.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online Version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113428
    Write-Debug 
    Write-Error 
    Write-Host 
    Write-Output 
    Write-Verbose 
    Write-Warning 



